Tomas Madariaga

1311 Bonita Ave 94709 Berkeley CA +1 510 338 2169

www.tomasmadariaga.com - es.linkedin.com/in/tomasmadariaga/en - www.github.com/tomasmax madariaga.tomas@gmail.com

PROFILE

Full stack developer, IT consultant, worked in Start-ups & Big B2B consulting company. Agile Project Management MSc. Big Thinker, Lifelong Learner, Entrepreneur, Business & Result oriented. Willing to create and learn new prototypes & solutions. Enthusiastic about improving my skills in Project & Product Management, Software Engineering, Innovation and Business.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer & Product Manager, San Francisco, Moovit

August 2016 - Present

Front end developer (HTML5, JavaScript, AWS). Work with UX/UI teams to bring wireframes, design to life. Serve as product manager to translate partner needs into development requirements. App & Web prototyping with proto.io

Android Developer & Consultant, Spain, Indra

January 2015 - July 2016

Consultancy and development of an Android <u>smart mobility solution</u> to speed up maintenance of several utility companies network. GIS back end with JBOSS server ESRI. Mobile, desktop dev Android, .NET. B2B Mobile

Freelance Project Management Coach, Bilbao, Fondo Formacion Euskadi

May - July 2015

Created a MOOC to increase some Coworking Space Managers Project Management efficiency, <u>PIRECOW</u> project.

Project Manager & Software engineer, Bilbao, Tenzing, Grupo Urbegi

February 2013 - December 2014

Managed a project that improves the <u>Council of Bizkaia's loan requests</u> filtering process, reducing their response time. Development of a <u>Crowdfunding platform</u>. Web & mobile full stack developer (RoR, Node.js, Hybrid, AWS).

Freelance Web Developer & Designer & Marketing

October – November 2013

Connect already developed online game with Facebook. Designed advertisements and marketing strategies to introduce a new IT product in the Spanish market.

Software Engineer Intern - Ruby on Rails, Java, Bilbao, Techabout

Machine Learning Specialization, University of Washington, Coursera

October 2011 - July 2012

2014

2016

2016

2015

Meetabout entrepreneurial project web development (back & front end) Ruby on Rails and Java OSGi.

Advanced Project Management Postgraduate Degree, University of Barcelona

EDUCATION

	•	Ū	U	0 ,	•	
РМВОК, РМ	P, Prince	2, Lean Proj	ject Managemer	nt, Six Sigma.	. Agile methodologies: Agile, Sc	rum
MSE in Indu	ustrial Er	gineering	(Business Man	agement), (GPA: 3.5, U. of Deusto	2010 - 2013
MSE in Bus	iness Eng	gineering,	(Erasmus), Solv	ay Brussels	School, Brussels, Belgium	2012 – 2013
MSE in Con	nputer So	cience, GP/	A: 3.5, Universi	ty of Deusto	o, Bilbao	2010 – 2013
BSc in Com	puter Sci	ence, GPA	: 3.2 University	of Deusto.	Bilbao	2007 – 2010

COMPLEMENTARY EDUCATION

Big Data Specialization, University of San Diego, Coursera

Lean IT Foundation Certification, APMG International

<u>Programming Mobile Services for Android Handheld Systems: Concurrency</u> by Vanderbilt University on Coursera <u>Programming Mobile Applications for Android Handheld Systems</u>, University of Maryland, College Park on Coursera <u>Bizkaia Talentia Program</u>, Selected because of my skills and academic record.

Software Engineering for Software as a Service, University of California, Berkeley, Coursera

2012

Ingenio: Innovation, Creativity and Entrepreneurship Program, University of Deusto, Bilbao

2011

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Java, C/C++, Ruby on Rails, Node.js, HTML5, JavaScript, SASS, LESS, CSS3, AngularJS, EmberJS, Bootstrap. Android and Cordova (Phonegap). MVC architecture. Professional experience in Back-end, Front-end, AWS and Heroku. Proficient with GIT and SVN. TDD. SQL, SQLite, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, AWS DB. AWS Big Data, Tableau, Pentaho and Rapidminer.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE & AWARDS

<u>Coursera's Global Translator Community (GTC) Volunteer</u>, translate subtitles for course lecture videos.

Physics and mathematics Private teacher

2013 – 2015

University of Deusto Business IX Forum Employment and Entrepreneurship Business Simulator winner.

2013 – 2015

2013 – 2015

2014